

# Dr Germán

Martinez-Ayuso

PhD, Software Developer

- germa89.github.io
- @ germanmartinezayuso@gmail.com
- in linkedin.com/in/gmartinezayuso
- github.com/germa89

## About me –

I am a civil engineer with software development focus. I do posses extensive experience in python programming, software development, and continous integrations continous deployment (CI/CD).

Experienced with machine learning algorithms such as KNN neighbours and neural networks, which I have applied to different research and business cases.

My interests are also related to civil engineering, more specifically materials modelling and structural design.

# Skills -

Programming (Python, Matlab, C++, ...)

Software development (CICD, OOP, ...)

Structural engineering (Finite element methods)

Data Analysis (Cleaning, Visualization, etc.)

Data science tools (Numpy, Pandas, etc.)

Machine learning (Sk-learn, TensorFlow)

Optimisation and algorithms

Spanish\*6, English\*6, French\*3, Logical thinking\*6, Problem oriented\*5, Communicative\*5,

(\*)-The skill scale is from 0 (Basic Awareness) to 6 (Expert).

## Experience

## 2023-Present Senior Research and Development Engineer

Ansys Inc

- Main maintainer of PyMAPDL library, an open source Python interface to Ansys MAPDL structural solvers.
- Co-owner of Ansys github enterprise organization. Help to maintain CICD pipelines and implementing best practices.
- Co-maintainer of MAPDL solver Ubuntu docker image. Containerization of applications for cloud deployment.
- Contributor to MAPDL solver and its gRPC data interface. Implementation of new methods to transfer data from the C++ application server to a Python client.

## 2022-2023 Research and Development Engineer II

Ansys Inc

- Contributor to PyMAPDL library. Supporting other Ansys libraries ansys/actions, ansys-tools-path, ansys-sphinx-theme, etc.
- Supporting the technological transformation of business units. Implementing best code practices, maintaining CICD pipelines in many organization packages, etc.

### 2020-2021 Research Officer in Data Science

Medical School, Cardiology department, Swansea University

- Application of machine learning algorithms (clustering and deep learning techniques) to detect abnormal behaviour in real cardiac cells optical data and fluorescent calcium measurements.
- Design and development of a workflow to analise of microscope images. Development of a graphic user interface in Python.

# 2019-2020 Research Fellow in Data Science for Materials Modelling Institute of Materials Discovery, University College of London

 Using numerical techniques based on finite element methods and machine learning techniques to optimise industrial composites such as honeycomb or recycled aggregates.

#### 2018-2019 **Project Officer in Manufacturing Analysis**

Project ASTUTE2020: Advanced Sustainable Manufacturing Technologie, Swansea University

 Application of techniques from the domain of data science such as data pre-processing, neural networks and multi constraint optimisation to reduce costs in steel manufacturing industry.

## Education

### 2015-2019 PhD in Civil Engineering

Swansea University (UK)

Micro to macro-scale material modelling using numerical techniques for energy harvesting applications. Fully-funded scholarship.

- Developed my own non-linear finite element code in Matlab for piezoelectric harvesters based on Euler-Bernoulli beams. Validated experimentally.
- Used commercial finite element packages to obtain the equivalent mechanical properties of micro composite structures (Homogenization).

#### 2010-2013 M.Eng. Civil Engineering

University of Alicante (Spain)

Strong background in numerical methods.

### 2007-2010 B.Eng. Civil Engineering

University of Córdoba (Spain)

Special award, Graduated with honours. Best student record award.